Mary van Kleeck Papers, 1849-1998
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES1900-1961
  - Social Work, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Social Workers for Smith]
    - General 1930-41, undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Industrial Research Group 1921 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Training Schools for Social Work 1920 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - War industry 1943-44 (Box 62, Folder 4-5)
  - Socialism 1931-57 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Southern states 1936-44 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Teggart, Frederick J., sociologist 1949-50 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Textile industry 1914-25, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Tuberculosis 1905-06, 1944 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Tugwell Bill 1934 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Unemployment, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Conference on Unemployment; Oversize Materials]
    - General 1928-47, [see also African Americans; Great Depression] (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Conferences1928-36 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Insurance 1930-45, [see also Social Insurance/Social Security] (Box 62, Folder 14-15)
    - Mayor's Committee on Unemployment 1915-16 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Reports and proposals 1928-39, undated (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Vigilantism 1933-37, undated, [see also Strikes] (Box 62, Folder 18)
  - Wages 1922, 1949-56, [see also Labor] (Box 62, Folder 19)
  - Women's charter 1936-39, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Women's employment, [see also World War I; World War II; SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation-Committee of Working Women; Women in Industry]
    - General 1916-26, undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - The Economic Position of Women: Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science 1910 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - World War I, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--YWCA]
    - Council of National Defense
      - Committee on Women in Industry 1917-23 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Nims, Marion R., Women in the War: A Bibliography 1918 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Storage Bulletin No. 9: "Employment of Women in the Storage and Warehousing Depots of the United States Army," 1917 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - War industries
      - Training 1917-18 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Wages 1917-18, undated (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - War Labor Administration 1918 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - War Labor Policies Board
      - Minutes 1918-19 (Box 63, Folder 10-11)
      - Regulations 1918 (Box 63, Folder 12)
      - Reports 1918 (Box 63, Folder 13-14)
      - "Women and the War Labor Board," circa 1919 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - World War II
    - Employment 1941-42 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - National Defense Mediation Board 1941 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - War Manpower Commission 1942-45 (Box 64, Folder 3-6)
    - Women in industry
      - Newspaper clippings 1941-45 (Box 64, Folder 7-9)
      - Printed materials 1942-44 (Box 64, Folder 10)
- SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES 1897-1961
  - Adelynrood Conferences, [see also Companionship of the Holy Cross]
    - Peace 1937 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Religious therapy 1945 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Social justice 1942-44, [see also National Conference on the Christian Way of Life] (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, [see International Industrial Relations Institute] (Box 65)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science 1930-44 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - American Association for Labor Legislation 1939 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - American Association of Social Workers
    - Central Council 1920-22 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee 1920-25 (Box 65, Folder 7-8)
    - Finance Committee 1921-23 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Future Program Committee 1925 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Publications Committee 1925-31 (Box 65, Folder 11-12)
    - Miscellaneous 1921-42 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - American Association of University Women
    - Correspondence 1923-35 (Box 65, Folder 14-16)
    - Equal Rights Amendment 1924-25, undated (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES-- Agriculture; Civil liberties; Labor]
    - Board 1935-41 (Box 65, Folder 18-22)
    - Bulletin 1939-40 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - By-laws 1939-40 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Committees
      - Civil Rights in Labor Relations 1938-40 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Standards for Local Organizations 1935-37 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Workers and Farmers Rights 1933-34 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Dies 1939-40 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Northern California 1935 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Conferences
      - Civil Liberties Under the New Deal, Washington, D.C. (8-9 Dec. 1934)1934-35 (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - National Conference on Civil Liberties in the Present Emergency, New York City (13-14 Oct. 1939)1939 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence 1931-41 (Box 66, Folder 10-11)
    - Financial 1934-39 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Legislation
      - General 1935-40 (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Anti-Facist 1937-38 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Madison Square Garden Meeting 1934 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Minutes 1937-40 (Box 66, Folder 16-19)
    - Newspaper clippings 1934-40 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets 1932-40, undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Statement to the President 1933-34 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - American Committee Against Fascist Oppression in Germany, [see SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Fascism] (Box 67)
  - American Economic Association 1942-43 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - American Federation of Labor: lists of affiliated organizations 1919-42 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - American Friends Service Committee 1935-41 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - American Labor Party 1934-53, undated [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Labor Party, 1928-44] (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - American League Against War and Fascism 1933-35 [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Fascism] (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - American League for Peace and Democracy 1938-39, undated (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - American League to Abolish Capital Punishment 1931-38 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - American Management Association 1923-26, undated (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - American Sociological Society 1951-54 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - American Statistical Association
    - General1924-40, undated (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Governmental Labor Statistics scrapbooks
      - United States newspaper clippings 1926 (Box 67, Folder 14-15)
      - Editorials 1926 (Box 67, Folder 16)
      - Labor, Foreign press, and News associations 1926 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Committee scrapbook 1929 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - The Art Workshop 1929-30, 1945 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Association of Federal Workers 1932-34 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Association of Workers in Public Relief Agencies 1935 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Boston Women's Trade Union League, [see National Women's Trade Union League] (Box 68)
  - Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers
    - General 1932-34 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Conflict with college 1934-35 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Report of the Fact Finding Committee 1935 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - "The Workers Look at the Stars," 1927 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace 1941 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - China Welfare Appeal, Inc. 1941-50, undated (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Church League for Industrial Democracy 1936-55, undated, [see also American Civil Liberties Union, American League Against War and Fascism; SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--William Spofford; SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Labor] (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - College Settlements Association 1901-26, [see also Intercollegiate Community Service Association; SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Daily activities files; SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Settlement Houses] (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Companionship of the Holy Cross 1922-23, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAS-Related archival collections-Sisters of the Holy Cross, SERIES VII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS-Audio materials-Frances Young] (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Communist Party 1936-60 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Conference on Elimination of Waste in Industry 1927 (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Conference on Unemployment 1927 (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Consumers' League
    - National 1932-49 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - New York
      - Business and correspondence 1929-34 (Box 68, Folder 19-21)
      - Printed material 1904-31, undated (Box 68, Folder 22)
  - Cooperative League of the United States of America 1942-44, undated (Box 68, Folder 23)
  - Correlated Enterprises 1931-36 (Box 68, Folder 24)
  - Council for Pan American Democracy 1938-42, undated (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - Council on African Affairs 1945-50, undated, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--African Americans] (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - Economic Institute for Study in the USA and the USSR 1933-34 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Emergency Peace Campaign 1937 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Episcopal League for Social Action
    - General 1949-54 (Box 69, Folder 3-4)
    - Clippings from The Witness 1950-53 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Farmer-Labor Party 1932-36, undated, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES-- Labor, Labor party] (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Federal Council of the Churches of Christ 1933-49 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Federation of American Scientists 1954-58, undated (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists, and Technicians 1934-37, undated (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Fellowship for Christian Social Order 1921-25, undated (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Feloship Society No. 11934, undated (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Ford Motor Company 1919-28, [see also American Civil Liberties Union; Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Special projects--Employees' Representation] (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Friends of Jesus, [see SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Countries--Japan--Christianity] (Box 69)
  - Friends of the Soviet Union 1933-34 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Hospites, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Refugees]
    - Aims 1933-45 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence
      - General 1933-46 (Box 69, Folder 15-18)
      - Businessl933-47 (Box 69, Folder 19-20)
    - Fellowships
      - General 1933-35 (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Kraus, Frau Meta 1910-38 (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Kraus, Dr. Siegfried 1934-42 (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Maass, Hermann 1933-35 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Salomon, Dr. Alice 1928-37 (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Weiland, Dr. Ruth 1933-46 (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Wilbrandt, Dr. Robert 1933-34 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Financial 1934-40 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Fundraising 1933-41 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Institute for Research in Social Science 1953-54 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Inter-American Conference on Problems of War and Peace, Mexico City 1945 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Inter-American Labor Conference, Havana, Cuba 1939 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Intercollegiate Community Service Association (formerly College Settlements Association) 1922-26 (Box 70, Folder 13-15)
  - International Association for the Study and Improvement of Human Relations and Conditions in Industry 1925 (Box 70, Folder 16)
  - International Business Conference 1944 (Box 70, Folder 17)
  - International Chamber of Commerce 1930-39 (Box 71, Folder 1-2)
  - International Christian Social Institute 1929-30, undated (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - International Conference in Defense of Children 1951-52, undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - International Conference of Social Work [see also National Conference of Social Work]
    - Proposals and preparations 1926-28 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Paris (July 1928)1927-29 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Frankfurt on Main (July 1932)1931-33 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - [London] (July 1936)1934-36 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Brussels (July 1940)1938-1939 [Note: Event never happened] (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - International Conference of Working Women
    - First, Washington, D.C. 28 Oct.-6 Nov. 1919 (Box 71)
      - Opening session28 Oct. 1919 (Box 71, Folder 10)
      - 29 Oct. 1919 (Box 71, Folder 11)
      - 30 Oct. 1919 (Box 71, Folder 12)
      - 31 Oct. 1919 (Box 71, Folder 13)
      - 1 Nov. 1919 (Box 71, Folder 14)
      - 4 Nov. 1919 (Box 71, Folder 15)
      - 5 Nov. 1919 (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - 6 Nov. 1919 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Second, Washington, D.C. 1920 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Third, Geneva 1921 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - International Economic Union 1954 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - International Federation of Trade Unions 1944-45 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - International Industrial Relations Institute (IRI)
    - Administration (Box 72)
      - History and purpose 1929-39, undated (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Constitution 1925-32 (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - Minutes and reports 1925-39 (Box 72, Folder 9-18)
      - Triennial report 1938 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Committee on Industrial Relations in the United States 1938-39 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Continuing Committee 1943-47 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Legal matters 1937 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Financial material 1930-32 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Membership and information
        - General 1927-43 (Box 73, Folder 6)
        - Canada 1929 (Box 73, Folder 7)
        - United States
          - Correspondence 1927-47 (Box 73, Folder 8)
          - Lists 1937-38, undated (Box 73, Folder 9)
          - Meetings 1937 (Box 73, Folder 10)
          - Newsletter 1928-40 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence
      - General 1927-43 (Box 73, Folder 12-14)
      - Voysey, E. Brenda 1928-31 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Publications
      - Distribution and sales 1930-40 (Box 73, Folder 16-17)
      - Inquiries 1930-38 (Box 73, Folder 18)
      - William Archer, The Great Analysis reprint 1930-32 (Box 73, Folder 19)
      - Alejandro Carrillo, Mexico's Resources for Livelihood 1938-39 (Box 73, Folder 20)
      - Mary Fleddérus, International Unemployment 1932-33 (Box 73, Folder 21)
      - Sonia Zunser Hyman, Economic Security and World Peace 1935-38 (Box 73, Folder 22)
      - K. Lønberg-Holm and C. Theodore Larson, Design for Increasing Productivity 1939-40 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Mary van Kleeck and Mary Fleddérus, On Economic Planning 1935-37 (Box 74, Folder 2)
      - World Power Conference 1931-38 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - World Social Economic Conference, World Social Economic Planning 1932-34 [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES--Monographs; SERIES VI. BOOKS FROM VAN KLEECK'S LIBRARY] (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Max Yergan, "Gold and Poverty in South Africa," 1938-39 (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous pamphlets 1930-36, undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - Quarterly journal proposal 1934-35, undated (Box 74, Folder 7)
      - Synthese 1938-46, undated (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous material 1932-40 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - Publicity 1927-39 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Conferences, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Photographs]
      - International Industrial Welfare Workers Conference, Normandy (July 1922)1924 (Box 74, Folder 11)
      - International Industrial Welfare Workers Conference, Holland (19-27 June 1925)1925 (Box 74, Folder 12)
      - Summer School, BavenoJune 1927 (Box 74, Folder 13)
      - IRI Congress: "Fundamental Relationships between all Sections of the Industrial Community," Cambridge27 June to 3 July 1928
        - General 1927-28 (Box 75, Folder 1)
        - Proceedings 1928 (Box 75, Folder 2-3)
        - Printed material 1927-29, undated (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Discussion meeting, Methods of Promoting Satisfactory Human Relations in a Scientifically Organized Industry, Germany 26 June-3 July 1929
        - Correspondence 1929, undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
        - Speeches and memos 1929 (Box 76, Folder 2)
        - Press releases, news clippings, and articles 1929-30 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - World Social Economic Congress, Amsterdam23-29 Aug.1931
        - Planning 1930-31 (Box 76, Folder 4)
        - Sessions and programs 1931 (Box 76, Folder 5-9)
        - Minutes of the general meeting 1931 (Box 76, Folder 10)
        - Proceedings 1931 (Box 76, Folder 11)
        - Press releases 1931 (Box 76, Folder 12)
        - Analysis and review 1931 (Box 76, Folder 13)
        - Postscript 1931-32 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - World Power Conference, Vienna (Aug. 1933)1932-33, 1931 (Box 77)
      - Regional Study Conference on Social and Economic Planning, New York City23 Nov. - 1 Dec. 1934
        - Program and participants 1934-37 (Box 77, Folder 2)
        - Press releases and articles 1934 (Box 77, Folder 3)
        - Publicity scrapbook 1934, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 77)
      - Abstracts of speeches 1934 (Box 77, Folder 4)
        - Speeches and reports 1934 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - Regional Conference, "The Next Ten Years," New York City(30 Nov. 1936)1936 (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - The World's Natural Resources and Standards of Living, The Hague30 Aug.-1 Sept. 1937
        - General 1937 (Box 77, Folder 7)
        - Summaries of papers 1937 (Box 77, Folder 8)
        - Papers 1937 (Box 77, Folder 9)
      - 38th Oxford Management Conference: Optimum Productivity in Modern Industry, Oxford 31 Mar. - 4 Apr. 1938
        - Planning 1936-38 (Box 77, Folder 10)
        - Papers 1938 (Box 77, Folder 11)
        - Post-conference correspondence 1938 (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Dinner conference, "Labor's Program in Mexico," New York City (22 June 1938)1938 (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Luncheon Conference, Carlos Conteras Labarca, Chile Aug. 1938 (Box 77, Folder 14)
      - Study Conference, Productivity and Standards of Living as Influenced by Industrial Relations, The Hague (1-3 Sept. 1938)1938-39 (Box 77, Folder 15)
      - Regional Study Conference, Industrial Relations and Standards of Living in Mexico and the United States, Mexico City 1-3 Sept. 1938 (Box 77)
      - General 1938-39 (Box 78, Folder 1)
        - Abstracts and summaries 1938 (Box 78, Folder 2)
        - Papers 1938 (Box 78, Folder 3)
        - Newspaper clippings 1938 (Box 78, Folder 4)
        - Hartley W. Barkley, "Our Good Red Neighbor" controversy 1938-39 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - 7th International Management Congress, Washington, D.C. 19-23 Sept. 1938 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - International Conference on Negro Life and Labor, New York City, (Oct. 1938)1937-38, [see also African Americans, American Friends Service Committee] (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - A Research Program in the Trade Unions on Housing in the United States, Washington, D.C. (30 June 1939)1939 (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - Research Group Conference, Methods on Productivity and Standards of Living, The Hague (29-30 Aug. 1939), 1939 (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Annual Summer Study Conference, The Influence of Government on Standards of Living, The Hague 31 Aug.-2 Sept. 1939 (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - Annual Summer Study Conference, Natural Resources and Production for Standards of Living--in War and in World Reconstruction, The Hague (Sept. 1941)1939-40 (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - Emergency World People's Conference, New York City (12-19 Oct. 1947)1947 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Subjects
      - Africa 1938 (Box 78, Folder 13)
      - American Academy of Political and Social Science 1933-40 (Box 78, Folder 14)
      - Carillo, Alejandro 1938-42 (Box 78, Folder 15)
      - China 1930-39, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Countries-China] (Box 78, Folder 16)
      - Lipmann, Dr. Otto 1929-30 (Box 78, Folder 17)
      - Lombardo-Toldano, Vicente 1938-45 (Box 78, Folder 18)
      - Neurath, Otto 1933, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE] (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Nigeria 1936-40 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Otlet, Paul 1930-32 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Printed materials 1930-39 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Radio broadcasts 1934-35 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Research Group 1935-43 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Social and economic planning
        - United States 1931-35, undated (Box 79, Folder 7)
        - World 1931-36, undated (Box 79, Folder 8)
      - Social Economic Laboratory 1935-36, undated (Box 79, Folder 9)
      - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (U.S.S.R.) 1932-37, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES-Countries-U.S.S.R.] (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - van der Leeuw, C.H. 1931, undated, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE] (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - World Trade Tribunal 1931-42 (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union 1935, undated (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - International Labor Defense 1935-37, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Civil liberties; Labor] (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - International Labor Office, [see League of Nations] (Box 79)
  - International Management Institute
    - General 1932-33, undated (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Bulletin 1927-33 (Box 79, Folder 16-17)
    - "L'Organisation Scientifique du Travail Agricole," 1929 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Urwick, L., "Rationalization Does Not Lead to Unemployment," 1930 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - Urwick, L., "The Pure Theory of Organization with Special Reference to Business Enterprise," 1930 (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - "Scientific Management in a Group of Small Factories," 1931 (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous pamphletsundated (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - International Student Service 1929-30 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - International Union for Child Welfare 1947-48, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Child welfare] (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - International Women's Conference, Paris Nov. 1945
    - General 1945, (includes misfiled document "Voluntary Parenthood is Responsible Parenthood," Speech by Marie-Helene Lafaucheux, 29 December 1960) (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Report on the Problems and Status of Women in the U.S. 1944-45, undated (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Interprofessional Association for Social Insurance (IPA) 1934-39 (Box 80, Folder 5-6)
  - Labor College of Philadelphia, [see Conference on Unemployment] (Box 80)
  - Labor Law Administration Conference, Milford, Pennsylvania Dec. 1922, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Labor-Legislation]
    - General 1922 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence 1922 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - League for Industrial Democracy 1932-42 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - League for Social Justice 1932-34 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - League of Nations, [see also United Nations]
    - General 1920-30 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper clippings 1929-54 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - International Labor Office
      - General 1933-50 (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - Advisory Committee 1932 (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - Committee on Women's Work 1929-47 (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - Press releases and newspaper clippings 1939-48 (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Printed materials 1943-47 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - League of Struggle for Negro Rights 1931-34, undated, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--African Americans] (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - League of Women Shoppers 1935 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - League of Women Voters 1931 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Maritime Federation of the Pacific 1935 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - National Association for the Benefit of Middle Age Employees 1929-31, undated (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - National Commission on Law Observance and Enforcement
    - Charts and tables 1930 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper clippings 1929-31 (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - National Conference of Social Work
    - General 1910-55 (Box 82, Folder 1-7)
    - Scrapbook 1934 (Box 82, Folder 8-10)
  - National Conference on the Christian Way of Life
    - General 1923, undated (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Commission on Industry 1922, undated (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Commission on Race Relations 1924-25 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - National Committee 1923-24, undated (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - National Consumers' League, [see Consumers' League] (Box 83)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Atomic energy]
    - General 1947-57 (Box 83, Folder 5-7)
    - Correspondence 1949-54 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - National Council of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions 1948-51 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - National Defense Management Conference 1940-41 (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, Inc. 1935-57 (Box 83, Folder 11)